影城新闻正在播出"冒险聚焦"节目
NEWSREEL ANNOUNCER: Movietown
News presents Spotlight on Adventure.
您正在收看的
What you are now witnessing
是文明社会未曾见过的影像
is footage never before seen
by civilized humanity,
南美洲的一处失落之地
a lost world in South America.
它潜藏在壮丽的天堂瀑布之下
Lurking in the shadow
of majestic Paradise Falls,
孕育着尚未被发现的动植物
it sports plants and animals
undiscovered by science.
敢问有谁能踏入这偏远之地呢?
Who would dare set foot
on this inhospitable summit?
所以 有请今天的主角
查尔斯・蒙兹!
Why, our subject today,
Charles Muntz!
我们敬爱的探险家
他的"冒险精神"号飞船
The beloved explorer lands
his dirigible the Spirit of Adventure,
于本州降落在新罕布什尔州
in New Hampshire this week,
为期一年的远征得以完成
completing a yearlong expedition
to the lost world.
这艘轻便的飞艇由蒙兹本人设计
This lighter-than-air craft
was designed by Muntz himself
它比22辆头尾相连的警车还长
and is longer than 22 prohibition
paddy wagons placed end to end.
现在有请我们的冒险家出场
And here comes the adventurer now.
他与他忠心的狗群形影不离
Never apart from his faithful dogs,
飞船的设计甚至考虑到了犬类的舒适
Muntz conceived the craft
for canine comfort.
它是座名副其实的空中宫殿
It's a veritable floating palace
in the sky,
设有犬类梳洗和自动跑步设备
complete with doggy bath
and mechanical canine walker.
当地人视蒙兹为精神偶像
And, Jiminy Cricket do the locals
consider Muntz the bee's knees.
并将他奉为上宾
And how!
去冒险吧!
Adventure is out there!
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
蒙兹这次又带回了什么?
NEWSREEL ANNOUNCER: But what
has Muntz brought back this time?
先生们 我带来了天堂瀑布的怪兽!
Gentlemen, I give you
the monster of Paradise Falls!
(PEOPLE GASP)
天呐 好一只庞然大物!
NEWSREEL ANNOUNCER:
And, golly, what a swell monster this is!
但这是什么动物呢?
科学家们连声称假
But what's this? Scientists cry foul.
国家冒险协会指责蒙兹伪造骨架
The National Explorer's Society
accuses Muntz
of fabricating the skeleton.
不!
No!
蒙兹被协会除名
NEWSREEL ANNOUNCER:
The organization strips Muntz
of his membership.
(GASPS)
蒙受巨大羞辱的蒙兹
发誓将重返天堂瀑布
NEWSREEL ANNOUNCER: Humiliated,
Muntz vows a return to Paradise Falls
并承诺将活捉此怪兽!
and promises
to capture the beast alive!
我保证会活捉怪兽
I promise to capture the beast alive,
如果做不到就永世不回来!
and I will not come back until I do!
(CROWD CHEERS)
就这样 我们的冒险家
再次启程以正其名
NEWSREEL ANNOUNCER: And so,
the explorer's off to clear his name.
一路顺风 查尔斯・蒙兹
Bon voyage, Charles Muntz,
祝你活捉天堂瀑布的怪兽!
and good luck capturing
the monster of Paradise Falls!
(IMITATING AIRPLANE)
查尔斯・蒙兹在此
NEWSREEL ANNOUNCER:
Here's Charles Muntz
驾着他著名的飞艇
piloting his famous dirigible.
(HORN HONKING)
他跨越了派克峰
He hurdles Pikes Peak.
他跨越了大峡谷
He hurdles the Grand Canyon.
(CARL GRUNTS)
他跨越了珠穆朗玛峰
He hurdles Mount Everest.
(GRUNTS)
他绕过了珠穆朗玛峰
He goes around Mount Everest.
还有他做不到的事吗?
Is there nothing he cannot do?
飞屋环游记
正如蒙兹本人所说 "去..."
Yes, as Muntz himself says,
"Adventure is..."
去冒险吧! 小心了!
ELLIE: Adventure is out there!
Look out!
是总统山! 没法打右舷!
Mount Rushmore! Hard to starboard!
必须让"冒险精神"号穿越总统山!
Must get Spirit of Adventure
over Mount Rushmore!
挺住 伙计 我的狗狗如何了?
Hold together, old girl.
How're my dogs doing?
(MIMICS BARKING)
启动所有引擎!
让我们升到26000英尺的高空吧
All engines, ahead full!
Let's take her up to 26,000 feet.
向南转舵18度
Rudders 18 degrees towards the south.
天气真好 东风10节
It's a beautiful day.
Winds out of the east at 10 knots.
能见度... 极高
将天气情况记录进航行日志
Visibility unlimited.
Enter the weather in the logbook.
哦! 下方有发现
我要把它带回去研究
Oh! There's something down there.
I will bring it back for science.
喔! 是只小狗! 啊 没时间了!
有风暴! 闪电冰雹同时来袭!
Aw! It's a puppy! Ah! No time!
A storm! Lightning. Hail.
- 你在这干嘛?
- 啊!
- What are you doing?
- Ahhh!
你不知道这里是高级会所吗?
Don't you know
this is an exclusive club?
只有冒险家能进来
Only explorers get in here,
不是什么带头盔和风镜的
街头小毛孩想进就能进的
not just any kid off the street
with a helmet and a pair of goggles.
你以为这样就能混进来吗?
是不是?
Do you think you've got what it takes?
Well, do you?
(STAMMERING)
好吧 欢迎加入
All right, you're in. Welcome aboard.
怎么了? 哑巴吗?
What's wrong? Can't you talk?
嘿 我不咬人的
Hey, I don't bite.
(STATIC ELECTRICITY BUZZING)
我们是一伙的了
You and me, we're in a club now.
我看到你的气球飞走了
我们去取吧
I saw where your balloon went.
Come on. Let's go get it.
我叫艾丽
My name's Ellie.
在那儿呢
There it is.
(GULPS)
往前走啊
Well, go ahead.
去啊
Go on.
(CARL SCREAMING)
(THUDDING)
(SIREN WAILING)
(SHOUTS)
喔
Ow.
嗨 小子!
Hey, kid!
(SCREAMS)
我觉得你可能需要点鼓励
Thought you might need
a little cheering up.
我有些东西要给你看看
I got something to show you.
一会儿你要看的东西
ELLIE: I am about to let you
see something
我以前从没给别人看过
I have never shown
to another human being.
这辈子从没有过!
Ever! In my life!
你得发誓不会告诉别人
You'll have to swear
you will not tell anyone.
划十字 快!
Cross your heart. Do it!
我的冒险之书
ELLIE: My Adventure Book.
你认识他的
You know him.
(GASPS)
查尔斯・蒙兹 大冒险家
Charles Muntz, explorer.
等我长大了 要去他去的地方
When I get big,
I'm going where he's going,
南美洲 和美洲差不多但在更南边
South America.
It's like America, but south.
想知道我会住哪吗?
Wanna know where I'm gonna live?
"天堂瀑布 失落的世界"
"Paradise Falls, a land lost in time."
我从图书馆的书上撕下来的
I ripped this right out of a library book.
(GASPS)
我要把我的会所搬到那儿
就安在瀑布的旁边
I'm gonna move my clubhouse there
and park it right next to the falls.
一旦我到了那儿
Who knows what lives up there.
谁知道有什么在等着我呢?
And once I get there?
我把后面的空页留给以后的冒险
Well, I'm saving these pages for
all the adventures I'm gonna have.
只是我不知道该怎么去天堂瀑布
Only I just don't know
how I'm gonna get to Paradise Falls.
没错! 你会开小飞船送我去!
That's it!
You can take us there in a blimp!
划十字! 发誓你会做到!
Swear you'll take us! Cross your heart!
快! 划十字!
好 你答应了 不能反悔哦
Cross it! Cross your heart!
Good, you promised. No backing out.
那明儿见了 小子 再见!
Well, see you tomorrow, kid. Bye!
去冒险吧!
Adventure is out there!
你不怎么说话啊
You know, you don't talk very much.
我喜欢!
I like you!
喔
Wow.
(WEDDING MARCH PLAYING)
(GUESTS CHEERING)
(INAUDIBLE)
(ALARM BUZZING)
(GROANS)
(GRUNTING)
(JOINTS CRACKING)
哈!
Hah!
(GRUNTS)
(SIGHS IN RELIEF)
(WHIRRING)
(LOCKS CLICKING)
(GRUNTS IN FRUSTRATION)
(CONSTRUCTION WORKERS
SHOUTING)
(MACHINES CLANGING)
史蒂夫 别跟我闹了!
MAN: Stevie, throw me a deuce!
挺壮观的哈 艾丽?
(SCOFFS) Quite a sight, huh, Ellie?
啊 信来了
Uh! Mail's here.
荫树橡木疗养院 乖乖
(SCOFFS) Shady Oaks Retirement.
Oh, brother.
唔
Hmm...
早啊 弗雷德里克森先生
需要帮忙吗?
Hey! Morning, Mr. Fredricksen.
Need any help there?
不用 噢 对了!
No. Yes!
告诉你们那位老板
你们这些家伙在毁我的房子
Tell your boss over there
that you boys are ruining our house.
跟您说一声
Well, just to let you know,
我老板很愿意接手您的老房子
my boss will be happy to take
this old place off your hands,
并且比上次的出价还高一倍!
and for double his last offer!
您觉得如何?
What do you say to that?
呃 这应该是"不"了哈?
Uh, I take that as a "no," then?
我已经和你们老板说得很清楚了
I believe I made my position
to your boss quite clear.
您把李子汁倒进了他汽车的油箱
You poured prune juice in his gas tank.
是的 那感觉挺好
来 让我和他说说
Yeah, that was good.
Here, let me talk to him.
(BULLHORN BEEPS)
穿西装的那个 没错 就是你
好好洗洗 臭虫!
You in the suit.
Yes, you. Take a bath, hippie!
我不是他的同伙!
I am not with him!
这不是闹着玩的
他会想法设法得到您的房子
This is serious!
He's out to get your house.
告诉你老板他能得到这房子
CARL: Tell your boss
he can have our house.
- 真的?
- 那也是我死了之后!
- Really?
- When I'm dead!
我当您说了"也许"
I'll take that as a maybe.
现在订购 你能获得相机
ANNOUNCER ON TV> Order now,
you get the camera,
还能获得打印机 4倍光学变焦
you get the printer, 4x optical zoom,
施耐德镜头 照片打印 SD卡
Schneider lens, photo printer, SD card.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
"下午好 我叫罗素"
"Good afternoon. My name is Russell.
"我是一名野外探险队员
隶属于54团第12小分队"
"And I am a Wilderness Explorer
in Tribe 54, Sweat Lodge 12.
"您今天需要什么帮助吗 先生?"
"Are you in need
of any assistance today, sir?"
不用
No.
- 我能帮您过马路
- 不用
- I could help you cross the street.
- No.
- 我能帮您过院子
- 不用
- I could help you cross your yard.
- No.
- 我能帮您过门廊
- 不用
- I could help you cross your porch.
- No.
我总得帮你过点什么
Well, I gotta help you cross something.
不用 我好得很
No. I'm doing fine.
"下午好 我的名字是罗素"
"Good afternoon. My name is Russell."
(CARL STAMMERING)
- 孩子 孩子
- "我是一名野外探险队员"
- Kid... Kid.
- "And I am a Wilderness Explorer
- "隶属于54团第12小分队"
- 我... 别说了 孩子!
- "in Tribe 54, Sweat Lodge 12."
- I... Slow down. Kid!
- "今天您需要什么..."
- 谢谢
- "Are you in need of any assistance..."
- Thank you,
- 但我不需要任何帮助!
- "....帮助吗 先生?"
- but I don't need any help!
- "...today, sir?"
RUSSELL: Ow.
说吧
Proceed.
- "下午好"
- 跳到最后吧!
- "Good afternoon..."
- But skip to the end!
看到这些了吗?
这些是我野外探险的徽章
See these? These are
my Wilderness Explorer badges.
你可能注意到少了一枚
那是帮助老人的徽章
You may notice one is missing.
It's my Assisting the Elderly badge.
如果拿到了
我就能成为高级野外探险队员了
If I get it, I will become
a Senior Wilderness Explorer.
"野外探险去啊!"
"The wilderness must be explored!"
嘎 嘎 啊!
Caw, caw! Raar!
(HEARING AID SCREECHES)
那样就太棒了! 会有个表彰大会
It's gonna be great!
There's a big ceremony,
老爸们都会去 并给我们别上徽章
and all the dads come,
and they pin on our badges.
所以说你想帮助老人家?
So, you want to assist an old person?
是的! 这样我就能升高级了
Yep! Then I'll be
a Senior Wilderness Explorer.
- 你听说过沙锥鸟吗?
- 沙锥鸟?
- You ever heard of a snipe?
- Snipe?
一种鸟 眼睛小而圆
Bird. Beady eyes.
每晚都溜进我的院子偷吃杜鹃花
Every night it sneaks in my yard
and gobbles my poor azaleas.
我又老又弱 抓不到它
如果有人能帮我就好了
I'm elderly and infirm. I can't catch it.
If only someone could help me.
- 我! 我! 我帮您!
- 不知你行吗 它可狡猾着呢
- Me, me! I'll do it!
- I don't know. It's awfully crafty.
你得拍三次手才能引它出来
You'd have to clap your hands
three times to lure it in.
我会找到的 弗雷德里克森先生!
I'll find him, Mr. Fredricksen!
向下过两条街就是它的洞了
如果你向下走...
I think its burrow is two blocks down.
If you go past...
过两条街 知道了 沙锥鸟
Two blocks down. Got it! Snipe.
过来吧 小鸟儿 小鸟儿
Here, snipey, snipey.
找到了记得带到这里来
Bring it back here when you find it.
沙锥鸟!
RUSSELL: Snipe!
好了 再向前 向前
STEVE: Okay, keep her coming.
Keep coming.
停 停 停!
And stop. Stop. Stop!
怎么 嘿! 嘿! 你!
Why... Hey! Hey, you!
你在干什么呢?
What do you...
What do you think you're doing?
- 很抱歉 先生
- 别碰这个
- I am so sorry, sir.
- Don't touch that!
不 不 不
我会帮您修好的
No, no, no.
Let me take care of that for you.
- 离我的邮箱远点!
- 嗨 先生 我...
- Get away from our mailbox!
- Hey. Sir, I...
你别碰它!
I don't want you to touch it!
噢!
Ow!
(GROANING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
史蒂夫 你还好吗?
MAN: Steve, you all right?
(POLICE SIREN WAILS)
抱歉 弗雷德里克森先生
OFFICER EDITH: Sorry,
Mr. Fredricksen.
我觉得你并不像个危险人物 拿着
You don't seem like
a public menace to me. Take this.
荫树橡木的工作人员
明早会来接您的 好吗?
The guys from Shady Oaks will be by
to pick you up in the morning, okay?
现在该怎么办呢 艾丽?
What do I do now, Ellie?
(SIGHS)
早啊 先生们
Morning, gentlemen.
早安 弗雷德里克森先生
准备好走了吗?
Good morning, Mr. Fredricksen.
You ready to go?
(CHUCKLES)
准备得不能再准备了
Ready as I'll ever be.
能帮我拿下这个吗?
Would you do me a favor
and take this?
我们一会儿在车上见
I'll meet you at the van in just a minute.
我得好好和老房子告别
I wanna say one last goodbye
to the old place.
当然了 您慢慢来吧
Sure. Take all the time you need, sir.
见得多了
他可能要去上第80次厕所
That's typical. He's probably
going to the bathroom for the 80th time.
他真该好好收拾收拾呢
(SCOFFS) You think he'd take better
care of his house.
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(CAR ALARM WAILING)
(CARL LAUGHING)
永别了 小子们!
我会在天堂瀑布给你们寄明信片的
So long, boys! I'll send you a postcard
from Paradise Falls!
耶!
Heh!
我们上路了 艾丽
We're on our way, Ellie.
(MUSICAL TWANGING)
(GRUNTS)
(CHUCKLES)
(SIGHS)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
呃?
Huh?
哼
Hmm.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(EXCLAIMS IN FRUSTRATION)
(YELLS)
你好 弗雷德里克森先生
是我 罗素
Hi, Mr. Fredricksen. It's me, Russell.
你在外头做什么 孩子?
What are you doing out here, kid?
我找到了沙锥鸟 跟着它到了您门廊下
I found the snipe
and I followed it under your porch,
但沙锥鸟有条长尾巴 更像只大老鼠
but this snipe had a long tail
and looked more like a large mouse.
(GASPS)
请让我进去吧
Please let me in.
不行
No.
哦 好吧 你可以进...
Oh, alright, you can come...
(PANTING)
来
(SWALLOWS)
(PANTING)
呃
Huh.
我从没坐过会飞的屋子
I've never been
in a floating house before.
(LAUGHS)
风镜啊 看看这玩意
哇哦! 您要去旅行吗?
Goggles. Look at this stuff.
Wow! You're going on a trip?
"天堂瀑布 失落的世界"
"Paradise Falls, a land lost in time."
您要去南美洲啊 弗雷德里克森先生?
You're going to South America,
Mr. Fredricksen?
别碰那个! 你会弄脏它的
Don't touch that! You'll soil it.
大多数人会坐飞机
You know, most people take a plane,
但您很聪明 因为这样您能带齐
电视 餐具和所有的东西
but you're smart because you will
have all your TV and clocks and stuff.
哇 您是这样驾驶房子的?
Whoa.
Is this how you steer your house?
真的管用吗?
Does it really work?
(IMITATING AIRPLANE)
小孩 你别去碰...
Kid, would you stop with the...
- 这样右转
- 不要动...
- This makes it go right.
- Let go of that...
- 这样就转左了
- 快住手
- And that way's left.
- Knock it off!
嘿 快看! 高楼大厦
Hey, look! Buildings.
那楼离这么近 我都能碰到了
That building's so close
I could almost touch it.
哇! 真棒!
RUSSELL: Wow! This is great!
您也该来试试 弗雷德里克森先生
You should try this, Mr. Fredricksen.
看啊 下面的公车站能送我回家
过两条街就到!
Look, there's a bus that could
take me home two blocks away!
嘿 这里能看到您的房子
Hey! I can see your house from here.
- 别乱动了 小孩
- 哇哦!
Don't jerk around so much, kid. Whoa!
(RUSSELL SCREAMING)
这办法恐怕不行
Well, that's not gonna work.
我认识那云 是积雨云
I know that cloud. It's a cumulonimbus.
您知道吗
Did you know that
当暖气流升到冷气流上面
the cumulonimbus forms
就会形成积雨云了?
when warm air rises over cool air?
整晚充气球为了什么啊?
Stayed up all night
blowing up balloons... for what?
所以就形成了闪电
...and that's how we get lightning.
- 说得好 孩子
- 弗雷德里克森先生?
- That's nice, kid.
- Mr. Fredricksen?
(HEARING AID SQUEAKS)
暴风雨要来了 越来越吓人了
(MUTED) There's a storm coming.
It's starting to get scary.
我们要被吹散了!
我们有大麻烦了!
We're gonna get blown to bits!
We're in big trouble...
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
- 你在那儿干嘛呢?
- 快看
- What are you doing over there?
- Look.
(WIND HOWLING)
看到了吗? 积雨云
See? Cumulonimbus.
(YELLS)
(YELLING)
我的背包!
My pack!
抓到了!
Got ya!
(YELLING)
(GASPS)
(GROANING)
(EXHALES IN RELIEF)
我还以为您死了呢
I thought you were dead.
出什么事了?
What happened?
我刚在掌舵 我做到了
我能驾驭飞屋了
I steered us. I did. I steered the house.
掌舵?
Steered us?
您把东西抱紧后就睡着了
After you tied your stuff down,
you took a nap.
所以我就跑前面掌舵
我们就到了这里
So I went ahead
and steered us down here.
那是
Yeah. Sure.
(GROANS)
我们迷路了
Can't tell where we are.
哦 我们已经在南美了
Oh, we're in South America, all right.
有了我的野外探险GPS 小菜一碟
It was a cinch
with my Wilderness Explorer GPS.
- GP什么?
- 我爸给我的
- GP... What?
- My dad gave it to me.
它能指示我们目前的所在地
It shows exactly where we are
on the planet.
(IMITATING GPS BEEPING)
有了这宝贝 我们永远不会迷路!
With this baby, we'll never be lost!
哎呀
Oops.
(CARL GROANS)
放你下去 坐公车回家吧
We'll get you down, find a bus stop,
你就说要回去找妈妈
you just tell the man
you wanna go back to your mother.
当然 但我觉得天堂瀑布没公车吧
Sure, but I don't think
they have buses in Paradise Falls.
好了 这样就行了
There. That ought to do it.
我再给你些零钱坐车
Here, I'll give you
some change for bus fare.
不用了 我可以用公交卡
RUSSELL: No, I'll just use
my city bus pass.
喔 那得转个无数站
RUSSELL: Whoa. That's gonna be
like a billion transfers
才能到我家了
to get back to my house.
弗雷德里克森先生 要多久着陆啊?
Mr. Fredricksen, how much longer?
我们升得挺高的
要花个几小时着落吧
Well, we're up pretty high.
Could take hours to get down.
(CARL EXCLAIMS)
那是楼房之类的吧
That thing was... building or something.
(CARL EXCLAIMS)
那是什么 弗雷德里克森先生?
What was that, Mr. Fredricksen?
我们应该还没到地吧
We can't be close to the ground yet.
(GASPS)
等等! 等等 不 不要!
不要 不要!
Wait! Wait, no, don't! Don't, don't!
等等 等等!
Wait, wait. Wait!
(CARL EXCLAIMING)
- 罗素 坚持住
- 哇哦!
- Russell, hang on! Hey!
- RUSSELL: Whoa! Whoa!
(RUSSELL EXCLAIMING)
啊啊啊啊啊!
Aaaagggghhhhh!
- 往回走 往回走
- 好的
- CARL: Walk back. Walk back.
- Okay.
加油 加油
CARL: Come on. Come on.
(RUSSELL GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
我们... 在哪儿呢?
Where... Where are we?
这里不像是城市或丛林
弗雷德里克森先生
This doesn't look like the city
or the jungle, Mr. Fredricksen.
(WIND HOWLING)
别担心 艾丽 我抓住了
Don't worry, Ellie. I got it.
瞧那儿
There it is.
艾丽 真是太漂亮了
Ellie, it's so beautiful.
我们成功了
We made it.
成功了! 罗素 我们能飞到那儿!
快爬上去 爬上去!
We made it! Russell! We could float
right over there! Climb up. Climb up!
你是说 帮助您?
You mean, assist you?
- 是的 是的 随便啦
- 好的 我这就爬
- Yeah, yeah. Whatever.
- Okay. I'll climb up.
(CARL MUTTERING)
(RUSSELL GRUNTING)
- 看着点!
- 抱歉
CARL: Watch it!
RUSSELL: Sorry.
(RUSSELL GRUNTING)
等你上去了 再把我吊上去!
Now, when you get up there,
go ahead and hoist me up!
知道了吗?
Got it?
(RUSSELL GRUNTING)
你到门廊了吗?
You on the porch yet?
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
什么? 就这样了?
What? That's it?
我好不容易到了这儿
结果被困在这堆石头上了?
I came all this way just to get stuck
at the wrong end of this rock pile?
好极了
Great.
(GRUNTING ANGRILY)
嘿 如果我帮您过去
你能来签发我的徽章吗?
Hey, if I could assist you over there,
would you sign off on my badge?
- 你在说什么?
- 我们能拖着房子去瀑布
- What are you talking about?
- We could walk your house to the falls.
- 拖着去?
- 是啊! 我们已经稳住它了
- Walk it?
- Yeah! After all, we weigh it down.
可以像拖气球一样拖着走
We could walk it right over there.
Like a parade balloon.
现在我们就快速而安静地
拖着房子去瀑布吧
CARL: Now, we're gonna walk
to the falls quickly and quietly
- 不要饶舌音乐或闪电舞
- 好的
- with no rap music or flash dancing.
- RUSSELL: Uh-huh.
我们最多有三天时间
不然气球里的氦气就漏光了
We have three days, at best, before
the helium leaks out of those balloons.
如果没到之前就没气的话
And if we're not at the falls
when that happens...
- 沙子
- 我们就到不了瀑布
- Sand.
...we're not getting to the falls.
我找沙子了!
I found sand!
别担心 艾丽
我们会把房子安在那儿的
Don't you worry, Ellie.
We'll get our house over there.
是不是觉得有趣了?
RUSSELL: This is fun already, isn't it?
等我们到了那里
您一定倍感受助于人
By the time we get there,
you're gonna feel so assisted.
哦 弗雷德里克森先生
如果我们不巧走散的话
Oh, Mr. Fredricksen,
if we happen to get separated,
用野外探险专用呼叫法
use the Wilderness Explorer call.
嘎 嘎 啊!
Caw, caw! Raar!
(HEARING AID SCREECHES)
等等 再问一句
我们为啥去天堂瀑布来着?
RUSSELL: Wait. Why are we going
to Paradise Falls again?
嘿 我们来玩个游戏
CARL: Hey, let's play a game.
叫做"看看谁安静的时间更长"
It's called
"see who can be quiet the longest."
酷! 我妈也爱玩这游戏!
RUSSELL: Cool!
My mom loves that game!
(GROWLING)
(HIGH-PITCHED SCREECHING)
(DOGS WHIMPERING)
(GROANING)
破玩意儿!
Darn thing!
(RUSSELL MOANING)
快点 罗素 你能不能快点?
Come on, Russell.
Would you hurry it up?
我累死了 膝盖好痛
I'm tired. And my knee hurts.
哪个膝盖?
Which knee?
我的手肘也好痛
而且我得上厕所了
My elbow hurts,
and I have to go to the bathroom.
我五分钟前才问过你
I asked you about that five minutes ago.
我那时确实不想嘛!
Well, I didn't have to go then!
我不想再走了 能停下么?
(MUFFLED) I don't wanna walk
anymore. Can we stop?
罗素 你再不快点
老虎就会来吃了你的
Russell, if you don't hurry up,
the tigers will eat you.
南美洲没有老虎 动物学常识
There are no tigers in South America.
Zoology.
(GROANS)
噢 看在老天的份上
到灌木丛里解决掉吧
Oh, for the love of Pete! Go on into
the bushes and do your business.
好 给你! 看好我的东西
Okay! Here! Hold my stuff.
我老早就想试试了
I've always wanted to try this.
弗雷德里克森先生
RUSSELL: Mr. Fredricksen,
我应该先挖坑还是后挖啊?
am I supposed to dig the hole
before or after?
(EXCLAIMS IN DISGUST)
我可不管!
None of my concern!
噢 该先挖的!
RUSSELL: Oh. It's before!
噢! 啦 啦 啦 啦 啦!
Bah!
La la la la la!
(SIGHS IN RELIEF)
嗯?
Huh?
脚印?
Tracks?
沙锥鸟
Snipe.
过来 沙锥鸟 出来啊 沙锥鸟
Here, snipe. Come on out, snipe.
沙锥鸟
Snipe.
嗯?
Huh?
(RUSTLING)
(GASPS)
哈 找到你了! 别怕 小鸟儿
Ha! Gotcha! Don't be afraid, little snipe.
我是野外探险家
我是大自然的好朋友
I am a Wilderness Explorer,
so I'm a friend to all of nature.
还想吃么?
Want some more?
(RUSSELL GASPS)
乖乖 别都吃光了 出来吧
Hi, boy. Don't eat it all. Come on out.
出来吧 出来吧 别怕 小鸟儿
Come on. Come on.
Don't be afraid, little snipe.
乖乖 可爱的小鸟儿 可爱的...
Nice snipe. Good little snipe. Nice...
大鸟
Giant snipe.
(FOOTSTEPS THUDDING)
- 我发现沙锥鸟了!
- 噢! 是吗!
- I found the snipe!
- Oh! Did you?
- 它们是不是很高?
- 噢 没错 它们确实很高
- Are they tall?
- Oh, yes, they're very tall.
- 是不是五颜六色的?
- 没错!
- Do they have a lot of colors?
- They do, indeed!
- 它们是不是喜欢吃巧克力?
- 噢 是啊... 巧克力?
- Do they like chocolate?
- Oh, yes... chocolate?
(SQUAWKS)
- 噢! 那是什么东西?
- 这是沙锥鸟!
- Gah! What is that thing?
- It's a snipe!
世上没有沙锥鸟这东西!
There's no such thing as a snipe!
- 但你说沙锥鸟吃了你的... 噢!
- 嘿
- But you said snipes eat your... Whoa!
- Hey!
(RUSSELL LAUGHING)
(BIRD COOING)
嘿! 快滚开! 嘿!
Go on! Get out of here! Go on!
(HISSES)
(RUSSELL LAUGHS)
噢!
RUSSELL: Whoa!
Whoa!
当心 罗素!
Careful, Russell!
嘿 看啊 弗雷德里克森先生
它喜欢我 喔!
(GIGGLING) Hey, look, Mr. Fredricksen.
It likes me. Whoa!
- 罗素
- 噢 别挠了! 好痒
- Russell!
- No, stop! That tickles.
快走开! 走开! 走!
CARL: Get out of here! Go on! Get!
(HISSES)
(EXCLAIMS)
噢 不 不 不! 凯文!
没事的 弗雷德里克森先生是好人
Uh-oh. No, no, no! Kevin!
It's okay. Mr. Fredricksen is nice.
- 凯文?
- 我刚给它取的名字
- Kevin?
- Yeah. That's his name I just gave him.
走开! 听到没! 快走!
嘿! 那是我的!
Beat it! Vamoose! Scram!
Hey! That's mine!
(GAGGING)
(RETCHES)
(GROANS)
走! 走! 快滚开!
Shoo! Shoo! Get out of here!
(SQUAWKS MOCKINGLY)
快! 快走吧!
Go on! Beat it!
(EXCLAIMS IN DISGUST)
(SQUAWKS MOCKINGLY)
我能留下它吗? 求求你了?
RUSSELL: Can we keep him? Please?
我来喂它 陪它散步
我会打理它的麻烦事的
I'll get the food for him. I'll walk him.
I'll change his newspapers.
不
CARL: No.
无论树木鱼儿或鼹鼠
都是探险家的好朋友
"An Explorer is a friend to all,
be it plants or fish or tiny mole."
- 狗屁不通
- 就是通的
- That doesn't even rhyme.
- Yeah, it does.
- 嘿 快看 凯文
- 什么?
- Hey, look. Kevin.
- What?
给我下来! 不准上去!
Get down! You're not allowed up there!
(BALLOON BURSTS)
(SPITS)
你马上给我下来!
You come down here right now!
老天!
Sheesh!
你能相信吗 艾丽?
Can you believe this, Ellie?
艾丽?
Ellie?
嘿 艾丽! 我能养这只鸟吗?
Hey, Ellie! Could I keep the bird?
唔 唔
RUSSELL: Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
她要我跟你说可以
She said for you to let me.
但是我跟他说不行
我跟你说了不行!
But I told him no. I told you no!
不 行
N-O.
我看到你了
I see you back there.
快走! 回你该去的地方!
去烦烦别人饶了我们吧
Go on! Get out of here! Shoo!
Go annoy someone else for a while.
嘿 那边的人 你们还好吗?
DUG: Hey, are you okay over there?
(KEVIN SQUAWKING)
恩 你好?
Uh... Hello?
噢!
CARL: Oh!
你好 先生! 谢天谢地
Hello, sir! Thank goodness.
能在这儿碰到人真是太好了
It's nice to know
someone else is up here.
我能闻到你们
DUG: I can smell you.
什么? 你能闻到我们?
What? You can smell us?
我能闻到你们
DUG: I can smell you.
嗨
Hey.
你在跟石头说话
(SNICKERS) You were talking to a rock.
嘿 那块看起来像只海龟
Hey, that one looks like a turtle.
快看那块! 像只狗
Look at that one!
That one looks like a dog.
(EXCLAIMS)
- 真的是只狗狗!
- 什么?
- It is a dog!
- What?
我家不允许养狗
We're not allowed to have dogs
in my apartment.
嘿 我喜欢狗狗
Hey, I like dogs.
你狗在我们这儿!
We have your dog!
- 喔!
- 这是谁家的狗?
- Whoa!
- Wonder who he belongs to.
坐下 乖狗狗
快看 他受过训练 握手
Sit, boy. Hey, look, he's trained. Shake.
Uh-huh.
- 说话
- 嗨 你好
- Speak.
- DUG: Hi, there.
(CARL AND RUSSELL GASP)
这狗刚刚是不是说 "嗨 你好"?
Did that dog just say "Hi, there"?
恩 是的
DUG: Oh, yes.
我叫道格 我对你一见钟情
My name is Dug.
I have just met you, and I love you.
(CARL STAMMERS)
我主人给我做了这个项圈
他人很好也很聪明
My master made me this collar.
He is a good and smart master,
他给我装了项圈
我就能说话了 有松鼠
and he made me this collar
so that I may talk. Squirrel!
我主人人好又聪明
My master is good and smart.
不可能
It's not possible.
噢 当然可能 因为我主人很聪明
DUG: Oh, it is,
because my master is smart.
- 太酷了 这是做什么用的?
- 嘿 你能不能...
- Cool! What do these do, boy?
- DUG: Hey, would you...
(DUG SPEAKING SPANISH)
我用这个项圈...
DUG: I use that collar...
(DUG SPEAKING JAPANESE)
...跟别人交流
请你住手吧
...to talk with.
I would be happy if you stopped.
罗素 不要碰那东西!
可能有辐射啥的!
Russell, don't touch that!
It could be radioactive or something!
我是个追踪高手
DUG: I am a great tracker.
我的同伴派我来独立执行
一项特殊的任务
My pack sent me on a special mission
all by myself.
你们见过一只鸟吗?
Have you seen a bird?
我的任务就是来找它
我追踪气味到了这里
I want to find one,
and I've been on the scent.
我是个追踪高手
我之前向你们提过吗?
I am a great tracker.
Did I mention that?
(HISSES)
嘿 就是这只鸟
DUG: Hey, that is the bird.
我从未这么近距离看过
但没错就是它了
I have never seen one up close,
but this is the bird.
我能把你的鸟作为俘虏
押回营地吗?
May I take your bird back to camp
as my prisoner?
好 好 带走吧 路上顺便学学
真正的狗是怎么叫的
Yes, yes, take it. And on the way,
learn how to bark like a real dog.
我会狗叫
DUG: I can bark.
(BARKS)
还有嚎叫
And here's howling.
(HOWLS)
(HISSES)
我们能留下它吗?
求你了 求你了 求求你了!
Can we keep him?
Please, please, please!
- 不行
- 但它是只会说话的狗诶!
- No.
- But it's a talking dog!
这肯定是什么鬼把戏
我们继续朝瀑布进发吧
It's just a weird trick or something.
Let's get to the falls.
请做我的俘虏吧
DUG: Please be my prisoner.
噢 求你了
噢 求你做我的俘虏吧!
Oh, please, oh, please be my prisoner!
(SNIFFING)
噢! 就是这儿了
我闻到那只鸟的气味了!
GAMMA: Oh! Here it is.
I picked up the bird's scent!
等一下 等一下 这是什么?
BETA: Wait a minute, wait a minute!
What is this?
巧克力 我闻到巧克力的气味
Chocolate. I smell chocolate.
我闻到李子和假牙的气味!
这都是些什么人?
GAMMA: I'm getting prunes
and denture cream! Who are they?
噢 伙计 主人不会满意的
BETA: Oh, man,
Master will not be pleased.
我们最好向他报告
有人抓住那鸟了 对吗 老大?
We better tell him someone
took the bird. Right, Alpha?
不
ALPHA: (IN SQUEAKY VOICE) No.
很快我们就会抓到那只鸟的
Soon enough the bird
will be ours yet again.
继续追踪气味 我的朋友
Find the scent, my compadres,
没有功劳也有苦劳嘛
and you too shall
have much rewardings
主人会多给一点奖赏的
from Master for the toil factor
you wage.
嘿 老大 你的项圈好像有点问题
BETA: Hey, Alpha, I think there's
something wrong with your collar.
你肯定撞到它了
You must've bumped it.
没错 你的声音听起来真滑稽!
GAMMA: Yeah,
your voice sounds funny!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
老二! 老三!
或许你们想要... 松鼠!
ALPHA: Beta! Gamma!
Mayhaps you desire to... Squirrel!
(GAMMA WHIMPERS)
或许你们想挑战一下我的权威
ALPHA: Mayhaps you desire
to challenge the ranking
这排位可是凭着
我的力量与智慧获得的
that I have been assigned
by my strength and cunning.
不 不 不 不过道格或许想试试
你可以问问他
BETA: No, no, no. But maybe
Dug would. You might wanna ask him.
我想他正在执行特别任务
找那个大鸟呢吧
GAMMA: Yeah. I wonder if he's found
the bird on his very special mission.
别哪壶不开提哪壶
ALPHA: Do not mention Dug
to me at this time.
这愚蠢的任务够他忙活的了
His fool's errand will keep him
most occupied. Most occupied indeed.
(LAUGHING EVILLY)
你们难道不同意我的看法吗?
Do you not agree with that
which I am saying to you now?
当然同意 可一旦主人发现
你让道格单独行动
BETA: Sure, but the second Master
finds out you sent Dug out by himself,
我们都没好果子吃
none of us will get a treat.
你们都是聪明的家伙
我可靠的伙伴们
ALPHA: (GROWLS) You are wise,
my trusted lieutenant.
我是老大 呼叫道格
快回话 道格
This is Alpha calling Dug.
Come in, Dug.
嘿 老大 你的声音好滑稽
DUG: (WHISPERING) Hi, Alpha.
Hey, your voice sounds funny.
我知道! 我知道!
你见到那只鸟了吗?
ALPHA: I know, I know!
Have you seen the bird?
噢 那只鸟已经是我的俘虏了
DUG: Why, yes.
The bird is my prisoner now.
哦 很好!
GAMMA: Yeah, right!
(HISSES)
不可能! 你在哪里?
ALPHA: Impossible! Where are you?
我跟那只鸟在一起
DUG: I am here with the bird,
我会把它带回来的
这样你们就会喜欢我了
and I will bring it back,
and then you will like me.
- 得挂了
- 嘿 道格 你在和谁说话呢?
- Gotta go.
- Hey, Dug, who you talking to?
- 不 等等 等等!
- 道格在干什么?
ALPHA: No, wait, wait!
BETA: What's Dug doing?
他为什么跟一个小男孩在一起?
GAMMA: Why's he with
that small mailman?
他们在哪里?
BETA: Where are they?
(BEEPING)
在那儿 我们走!
ALPHA: There he is. Come on!
噢 求你了 噢 求你了
噢 求求你做了我的俘虏吧
DUG: Oh, please, oh, please,
oh, please be my prisoner.
道格 不要再烦凯文了!
RUSSELL: Dug, stop bothering Kevin!
那位先生说我可以带走这只鸟
DUG: That man there says
I can take the bird,
而且我喜欢那位先生
就像喜欢我主人一样
and I love that man there
like he is my master.
我才不是你主人!
CARL: I am not your master!
我再次警告你 大鸟
DUG: I am warning you
once again, bird.
- 嘿! 放开它
- 我跳上来咯 大鸟
- Hey! Quit it!
- DUG: I am jumping on you now, bird.
罗素 照这个速度
我们永远也到不了瀑布
Russell, at this rate,
we'll never get to the falls.
来吧 大鸟
DUG: Here, bird.
(GRUNTS)
(CRASHING)
(GASPS)
我不是谁的主人 听到没?
I am nobody's master, got it?
我不想看到你
我也不想看到你!
I don't want you here,
and I don't want you here!
我受够你了!
I'm stuck with you!
要是我数到3 你俩还没消失...
And if you two don't clear out of here
by the time I count to three...
球! 噢 伙计 噢 伙计! 球!
DUG: A ball! Oh, boy, oh, boy!
A ball!
球? 你想要这个 狗狗?
Ball? Yeah, yeah? You want it, boy?
嗯? 嗯? 耶 耶?
Huh? Huh? Yeah. Yeah?
是的 我老早就想要这球了
DUG: Yes, I do!
I do ever so want the ball.
- 去捡吧
- 噢 太好了! 噢 太好了!
- Go get it!
- DUG: Oh, boy! Oh, boy!
我会捡回来的!
I will get it and then bring it back!
快点 罗素 给我些巧克力
Quick, Russell.
Give me some chocolate.
- 为什么?
- 给我就是了!
- Why?
- Just give it to me!
大鸟 大鸟!
Bird. Bird!
(KEVIN SQUAWKING)
快走 罗素
Come on, Russell.
等等 等等 弗雷德里克森先生
Wait. Wait, Mr. Fredricksen.
(CARL YELLS)
我们这是在做什么?
RUSSELL: What are we doing?
噢 我们走得够远了
凯文会想我的
Hey, we're pretty far now.
Kevin's gonna miss me.
(PANTING)
我想那招应该奏效了
I think that did the trick.
嗨 主人
DUG: Hi, Master.
没用
Afternoon.
(SQUAWKS)
(MUTTERING)
谢谢你让我们躲雨 艾丽
Well, thanks for keeping us
dry anyway, Ellie.
哪个是在前面的?
Which one's the front?
噢 孩子
Oh, boy.
这是第三步还是第五步?
Is this step three or step five?
(SCOFFS)
好了
RUSSELL: There.
(GRUNTING)
(TENT POLE SNAPS)
帮你搭好了
All done! That's for you.
噢...
Oh...
搭帐篷真难
Tents are hard.
你不是超级野外探险家么?
还有那什么GPM和奖章?
Wait. Aren't you super wilderness guy,
with the GPMs and the badges?
是的 我能告诉你个秘密吗?
Yeah, but can I tell you a secret?
- 不
- 好吧 秘密是...
- No.
- All right. Here it goes.
我其实从来没搭过帐篷
好了 我说出来了
I never actually built a tent before.
There, I said it.
你以前不是野营过吗?
You've been camping before,
haven't you?
是的 但是从未在野外
Well, never outside.
那你为什么不向你爸爸
讨教讨教怎么搭帐篷?
Well, why didn't you ask your dad
how to build a tent?
我想他不会跟我聊这些的
I don't think he wants
to talk about this stuff.
你不问怎么能知道
也许他比你想得更在行噢
Well, why don't you try him sometime.
Maybe he'll surprise you.
他总是出差 我不常见到他
Well, he's away a lot.
I don't see him much.
他总有回家的时候吧
He's gotta be home sometime.
我会打电话给他 但菲利丝说
我这样太打搅他了
Well, I call, but Phyllis told me
I bug him too much.
菲利丝? 你就这样直呼妈妈的名字
Phyllis? You call your own mother
by her first name?
菲利丝不是我妈妈
Phyllis isn't my mom.
噢
Oh.
但是他保证会来参加
我的探险家授奖仪式
But he promised
he'd come to my Explorer ceremony
亲自把助老奖章给我戴上
to pin on
my Assisting the Elderly badge.
到时他就能教我搭帐篷了 对吧?
So, he can show me
about tents then, right?
你要不要睡一会?
Hey, why don't you get some sleep?
我可不想吵醒这些
逃亡的马戏团成员
Don't wanna wake up
the traveling flea circus.
(SNORING)
弗雷德里克森先生?
Mr. Fredricksen?
道格说他要抓凯文做俘虏
Dug says he wants
to take Kevin prisoner.
我们得保护它
We have to protect him.
(YAWNING)
凯文能跟我们一起走吗?
Can Kevin go with us?
好吧 它可以
All right, he can come.
保证你不会丢下它?
Promise you won't leave him?
- 好的
- 划十字?
- Yeah.
- Cross your heart?
划十字
Cross my heart.
我这是招谁惹谁了我 艾丽?
What have I got myself into, Ellie?
(CARL SNORING)
(CROAKING)
(GROANING)
早安 甜心
Morning, sweetheart.
我们得快点了
We better get moving.
大鸟走了
Bird's gone.
也许罗素不会注意到
好咧 大家都起床吧!
Maybe Russell won't notice.
All right, everybody up!
凯文呢? 他不见了!
凯文! 道格 快去找凯文!
Where's Kevin? He's wandered off!
Kevin! Dug, find Kevin!
找鸟 找鸟! 这儿!
DUG: Find the bird, find the bird!
Hi, hi. Point!
瞧 它在那里!
Look. There he is!
(SQUAWKS)
那儿!
DUG: Point!
嘿 那是我的食物!
给我从屋顶上下来!
Hey! That's my food! Get off my roof!
对 从屋顶上下来
DUG: Yeah, get off of his...
(WOOFS)
(CHICKS HONKING IN DISTANCE)
(HONKS)
它在干什么?
What is it doing?
那只鸟在回应她的孩子
DUG: The bird is calling to her babies.
她的孩子
Her babies.
凯文是女的?
Kevin's a girl?
(HONKS)
她的家在那边的乱石林里
DUG: Her house is over there
in those twisty rocks.
她是出来给孩子找食物的
现在得回去喂它们了
She has been gathering food for
her babies and must get back to them.
(KEVIN COOS)
等一下 凯文要走了?
Wait. Kevin's just leaving?
(HISSES)
你答应过要保护她的
But you promised to protect her.
她的孩子需要她
我们得让他们团聚!
Her babies need her.
We gotta make sure they're together!
抱歉 罗素
我们已经耽误太多时间了
Sorry, Russell.
We've lost enough time already.
Yeah.
(RUSTLING)
(SQUAWKS)
这是她最喜欢的巧克力
This was her favorite chocolate.
因为她走了 所以有多的给你了
Because you sent her away,
there's more for you.
啊?
Huh?
凯文?
Kevin?
(RUSTLING)
(BARKING)
(CARL AND RUSSELL YELLING)
(GROWLING)
(BOTH WHIMPERING)
那只鸟在哪里?
你说你抓到那只鸟了
ALPHA: Where's the bird?
You said you had the bird.
噢 没错 噢 没错
DUG: Oh, yes. Oh, yes.
既然我这么说了
我知道你现在会怎么想
Since I have said that,
I can see how you would think that.
- 它在哪里?
- 嗯 明天
ALPHA: Where is it?
DUG: Uh... Tomorrow.
明天再来
到时那只鸟就又是我的了
Come back tomorrow, and then
I will again have the bird. Yes.
(SNARLING)
你追丢了!
为什么我都不感到吃惊?
ALPHA: You lost it!
Why do I not have a surprised feeling?
至少你让我们找到了这个小男孩
Well, at least you now have led us
to the small mailman
还有那个闻起来像李子的人
and the one who smells of prunes.
(WHIMPERS)
我们找到他们 主人定会高兴的
ALPHA: Master will be most pleased
we have found them
还会问他们很多问题 走吧!
and will ask of them many questions.
Come!
等一下 我们才不跟你们走呢!
我们要去瀑布!
Wait. We're not going with you!
We're going to the falls!
(BARKING)
(BOTH YELL)
滚开!
Get away from me!
(DOGS GROWLING)
让开
CARL: Get down!
(GASPING)
(ALL GROWLING)
(GASPS)
停下!
MUNTZ: Stay!
你坐那玩意儿来的?
You came here in that?
哦 没错
Uh, yeah.
一座房子? 一座飞屋?
MUNTZ: In a house? A floating house?
(LAUGHING)
(LAUGHING NERVOUSLY)
这是我见过的最荒谬的事
That is the darnedest thing
I've ever seen.
你们不是来抓我的鸟的吧?
You're not after my bird, are you?
但如果你要借点糖之类的
But if you needed to borrow
a cup of sugar,
我很乐意效劳
I'd be happy to oblige.
(DOGS LAUGHING)
好了 这都是个误会
Well, this is all a misunderstanding.
我的狗狗们弄错了
My dogs made a mistake.
等一下 你是查尔斯・蒙兹?
Wait. Are you Charles Muntz?
是的 我就是
Yeah, well, yes.
那个查尔斯・蒙兹?
THE Charles Muntz?
"去冒险吧!"
"Adventure is out there!"
真的是他! 那是查尔斯・蒙兹!
It's really him! That's Charles Muntz!
- 真的? 谁是查尔斯・蒙兹?
- 他!
- It is? Who's Charles Muntz?
- Him!
- 没错! 没错 真是他!
- 我是卡尔・弗雷德里克森
- DOGS: Yes! Yes! That's him!
- I'm Carl Fredricksen.
我和我妻子都是你的铁杆粉丝
My wife and I,
we were your biggest fans.
噢 品味不错
Oh, well. You're a man of good taste.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
好了 你们肯定累了 饿吗?
Now, you must be tired. Hungry?
Uh-huh.
好了 听着 各位!
Now, attention, everyone!
这些人不再是入侵者!
他们是我们的座上宾
These people are no longer intruders!
They are our guests.
(DOGS CHEERING)
跟我来 我挺喜欢你
DOG 1: Follow me.
I like you temporarily.
你闻起来确实像李子
You do smell like prunes.
哇!
CARL: Whoa!
我不会咬你
DOG 2: I will not bite you.
那小邮差闻上去像巧克力
DOG 3: The small mailman
smells like chocolate.
我为狗狗的行径道歉
MUNTZ: I'm sorry about the dogs.
- 希望他们没有过分粗鲁
- 我们没有
- Hope they weren't too rough on you.
- GAMMA: We weren't.
把你的飞屋栓在我的旁边吧
MUNTZ: Go ahead and moor
your airship right next to mine.
我们真的要进入"冒险精神"号?
We're not actually going inside
the Spirit of Adventure itself?
噢...
Oh...
你愿意吗?
Would you like to?
荣幸至极
Would I?
(LAUGHING DELIGHTEDLY)
稍等一下 蒙兹先生
CARL: Wait up, Mr. Muntz.
我的天呐
Jiminy Cricket.
- 你不行
- 我们拿道格怎么办?
BETA: Not you.
GAMMA: What do we do with Dug?
他跟丢了大鸟 给他戴耻辱罩
ALPHA: He has lost the bird.
Put him in the Cone of Shame.
(WHIMPERS)
我不喜欢耻辱罩
DUG: I do not like the Cone of Shame.
大部分的藏品都被
世界一流的博物馆收藏了
MUNTZ: Well, most of the collection
is housed in the world's top museums,
纽约 慕尼黑 伦敦
当然 我把最好的留给自己
New York, Munich, London.
Of course, I kept the best for myself.
你居然有这么多! 瞧瞧啊!
Did you ever! Will you look at that?
那是重脚兽
MUNTZ: Oh, yes, the Arsinoitherium.
我刷牙的时候 那个野兽来攻击我
Beast charged
while I was brushing my teeth.
我用剃须刀把它制服了
Used my shaving kit to bring him down.
噢 真是吃惊
Oh, yeah. Well, surprise me.
那时候 能把它从埃塞俄比亚
带出来的唯一方法
Only way to get it out
of Ethiopia at the time
就是谎称它是牙科器具
was to have it declared
as dental equipment.
老天! 索马里巨型豹龟!
Oh, my gosh!
The giant Somalian leopard tortoise!
你认出来了 真是佩服
Oh, you recognize it. I'm impressed.
那可是段有趣的经历
That's an interesting story there.
选得好
Excellent choice.
是我和罗斯福探险的时候找到的
I found it on safari with Roosevelt.
我们养成了晚上玩纸牌的习惯
He and I fell into a habit
of playing gin rummy in the evenings,
他居然作弊!
and did he cheat!
哦 他可真烂!
Oh, he was horrible.
主人 晚餐准备好了
ALPHA: Master, dinner is ready.
哦 翻译器坏了
Oh, dear. Broken translator.
电线又松了 好了 伙计
It's that loose wire again.
There you go, big fella.
谢谢 主人
ALPHA: (IN DEEP VOICE)
Thank you, Master.
我喜欢它刚才的声音
I liked his other voice.
(LAUGHING)
晚餐好了 这边请
Well, dinner is served. Right this way.
美国现在咋样了啊?
So, how are things stateside, huh?
好几次都想回去了
Almost tempted to go back a few times,
但我在这里还有未完成的工作
but I have unfinished work here.
但愿你们都饿了
Please. I hope you're hungry,
因为老五是我最好的厨师
because Epsilon is the finest chef
I've ever had.
(BARKS)
老五 你又做了这道菜!
Oh, Epsilon, you've done it again!
好耶!
Yes!
嘿嘿!
Hey! Hey!
哦 艾丽肯定会喜欢这些的
Oh, my Ellie would've loved all this.
因为你 她才有了这个梦想
You know, it's because of you
she had this dream
来到这里 住在天堂瀑布边上
to come down here
and live by Paradise Falls.
真是荣幸 现在你做到了
I'm honored. And now you've made it.
不会打扰你吧? 我不喜欢麻烦人
You're sure we're not a bother?
I'd hate to impose.
不不 有客人来真好
这才算是个宴请嘛
No, no. It's a pleasure to have guests,
a real treat.
- 宴请 哪有宴请!
- 宴请
DOG 1: Treat! Where's the treat!
DOG 2: Treat!
(DOGS CLAMOURING)
不不 安静! 都给我安静
MUNTZ: No, no. Quiet!
Calm down, calm down.
- 我要好吃的! 我要好吃的!
- 嘿!
- DOG 3: I want a treat! I want a treat!
- Hey!
我真不应该用那个词
I shouldn't have used that word.
有朋自远方来 不亦乐乎
Having guests is a delight.
经常有小偷来偷我东西
More often I get thieves
come to steal what's rightfully mine.
不!
No!
他们说我是骗子
They called me a fraud, those...
(EXCLAIMS)
但只要我把这东西带回去
我就能为自己正名了
But once I bring back this creature,
my name will be cleared.
漂亮吧?
Beautiful, isn't it?
我花了一生来找它
I've spent a lifetime tracking it.
有时候 追着追着 几年就过去了
Sometimes years go by
between sightings.
我试过用烟把它从窝里熏出来
I've tried to smoke it out of that
deathly labyrinth where it lives.
但之后人也就进不去了
You can't go in after it.
一旦进去 就出不来了
Once in, there's no way out.
好多狗都死了
I've lost so many dogs.
可现在那些恶棍又跑来
说什么那只鸟是他们的
And here they come, these bandits,
and think the bird is theirs to take.
很快他们就会发现
这座山可是非常危险的
But they soon find that this mountain
is a very dangerous place.
嘿 那个好像凯文
Hey, that looks like Kevin.
- 凯文?
- 是啊 那只大鸟是我的新宠物
- Kevin?
- Yeah, that's my new giant bird pet.
我训练它跟着我们
I trained it to follow us.
跟着你们? 不可能 怎么练法?
Follow you? It's impossible. How?
- 它喜欢吃巧克力
- 巧克力?
- She likes chocolate.
- Chocolate?
我把自己的巧克力给她吃
它超爱吃的
Yeah. I gave her some of my chocolate.
She goes gaga for it.
可是它跑了 已经不见了
But it ran off. It's gone now.
Carl 那些路过这里的人
You know, Carl, these people
who pass through here,
总是会说些好听的故事
they all tell pretty good stories.
一个测绘员绘制了一张地图
A surveyor making a map.
一个植物学家将各种植物分类
A botanist cataloguing plants.
一个老头乘着自己的屋子
来到天堂瀑布
An old man taking his house
to Paradise Falls.
这可是最动听的一个了
我都等不及要听它的结局了
I mean, that's the best one yet.
I can't wait to hear how it ends.
(GASPS)
真是个愉快的夜晚
但是我们必须得走了
Well, it's been a wonderful evening,
but we better be going.
你们不能走
Oh, you're not leaving.
我们不想利用你的热情好客
We don't want to take advantage
of your hospitality.
- 过来 罗素
- 可我们还没吃甜点呢
- Come on, Russell.
- But we haven't even had dessert yet.
孩子说得对 你们还没吃甜点
The boy's right.
You haven't had dessert.
老五做的樱桃派可好吃了
Epsilon here makes
a delicious cherries jubilee.
我坚决要求你们留下来
Oh, you really must stay. I insist.
我们还有好多要说呢
We have so much more to talk about.
(KEVIN WAILS)
凯文?
Kevin?
(WAILING)
它在这儿
It's here.
抓住他们!
Get them!
(BARKING)
- 快点!
- 我已经快了!
- Hurry!
- RUSSELL: I am hurrying!
啊! 他们来了!
Ahhh! They're coming!
主人 来这边
DUG: Master, over here.
(BOTH YELL)
向着光走 主人!
DUG: Go toward the light, Master!
(GRUNTING)
(SQUAWKS)
罗素!
Russell!
(SCREAMING)
滚回去!
Get back!
快走 主人! 我去拦住那些狗
DUG: Go on, Master!
I will stop the dogs!
你们这些狗 都给我停下
Stop, you dogs.
(YELPS)
Whoa!
(SCREAMING)
救命!
RUSSELL: Help!
Help!
救命!
嘎 嘎 啊!
Caw, caw! Raar!
把手给我!
Give me your hand!
抓紧凯文!
Hang on to Kevin!
(SCREECHES)
(CARL EXCLAIMS)
(GROANS)
(DOGS BARKING)
(PANTING)
(SIGHS)
凯文
RUSSELL: Kevin.
(WHIMPERS)
(CHICKS WAILING IN DISTANCE)
(HONKING)
不不不 凯文 别动
Oh, no, no, no. Kevin. Stay down.
她伤得很重
我们能不能帮她回家?
She's hurt real bad.
Can't we help her get home?
(SIGHS)
好吧 但我们得快点
All right, but we gotta hurry.
(DOGS WHIMPERING)
(MUNTZ SIGHS)
你们跟丢了他们?
You lost them?
不 是道格干的
BETA: No, it was Dug.
是的 它跟他们是一伙的
它帮他们逃跑!
GAMMA: Yeah. He's with them.
He helped them escape!
(EXCLAIMS ANGRILY)
等等
Wait.
等一下 道格
Wait a minute. Dug.
(RADAR BEEPING)
(SNIFFING)
看到什么了?
See anything?
没看见 那群笨狗没来追我们
DUG: No. My pack is not following us.
Boy, they are dumb.
真是疯了
This is crazy.
我终于见到了童年时代的偶像
可他却要杀了我们 真是可笑至极!
I finally meet my childhood hero,
and he's trying to kill us. What a joke!
嘿 我知道一个笑话
DUG: Hey, I know a joke.
一个松鼠爬到树上说
A squirrel walks up to a tree and says,
"我忘了储存橡栗过冬
现在我死了"
"I forgot to store acorns for winter
and now I am dead."
哈！真逗 因为那松鼠真的死了
Ha! It is funny
because the squirrel gets dead.
(HOUSE CRASHING)
小心 罗素
CARL: Careful, Russell.
你还好吗 凯文?
You okay, Kevin?
(WHIMPERS)
弗雷德里克森先生 你知道吗?
You know what, Mr. Fredricksen?
野外跟我想的不太一样
The wilderness isn't quite
what I expected.
是吗? 为什么?
CARL: Yeah? How so?
太荒芜了
It's kind of wild.
我是说 跟我在书上见到的不一样
I mean, it's not how they made it sound
in my book.
慢慢习惯吧 孩子
(SCOFFS) Get used to that, kid.
我爸说得可简单了
My dad made it sound so easy.
他真的很擅长露营
He's really good at camping
还会用石头取火
and how to make fire
from rocks and stuff.
以前每次帐篷大会 他都会来
He used to come to all
my Sweat Lodge meetings.
之后我们就去芬顿斯吃冰激凌
And afterwards,
we'd go get ice cream at Fentons.
我总是点巧克力的 他点黄油脆饼
I always get chocolate
and he gets butter brickle.
然后我们就坐在路边
Then we sit on this one curb
right outside,
我数所有蓝色的车子
他数红色的
and I'll count all the blue cars
and he counts all the red ones,
谁数的最多就赢了
and whoever gets the most wins.
我喜欢那条路
I like that curb.
也许听着很无聊
That might sound boring,
但无聊的事却是我最难忘的
but I think the boring stuff
is the stuff I remember the most.
(CHICKS WAILING IN DISTANCE)
(WAILING)
看! 在那边!
Look! There it is!
嘿 孩子 慢点
罗素 站着别动
Hey, kid. Hold on, Russell. Stand still.
(BIRDS WAILING)
瞧那鸟跑得多快
等等 你这只长过头的大母鸡
Look at that bird go.
Wait up, you overgrown chicken.
(CARL LAUGHS)
去吧 凯文
去找你的宝宝吧!
That's it. Go, Kevin!
Go find your babies!
跑啊 凯文 快跑!
Run, Kevin! Run!
哦 不!
Oh, no!
罗素 把你的刀给我!
Russell, give me your knife!
放开我的鸟!
MUNTZ: Get away from my bird!
(GASPS)
(KEVIN WAILS)
不!
No!
(DOGS BARKING)
不!
RUSSELL: No!
(KEVIN WAILING)
小心点
我要把它完好无损地带回去
MUNTZ: Careful. We'll want her
in good shape for my return.
放开它! 住手!
RUSSELL: Let her go! Stop!
凯文!
Kevin!
(CARL GRUNTING)
(CARL BREATHING HEAVILY)
你把凯文放走了
RUSSELL: You gave away Kevin.
你把她放走了
You just gave her away.
我才不管这些
我可没想到会这样！
This is none of my concern.
I didn't ask for any of this!
主人 没事的
DUG: Master, it's alright.
我不是你主人!
I am not your master!
如果你没出现 这一切就不会发生
And if you hadn't have shown up,
none of this would've happened!
恶狗! 恶狗!
Bad dog! Bad dog!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
现在 不管你要不要帮我
Now, whether you assist me or not,
只要我没死 我就要去天堂瀑布
I am going to Paradise Falls
if it kills me.
(HOUSE CREAKING)
(WATERFALL RUMBLING)
我不想要这些徽章了
Here. I don't want this anymore.
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
(SIGHS)
罗素?
Russell?
罗素!
Russell!
我要去帮凯文
你不去我也要去!
I'm gonna help Kevin, even if you won't!
(LEAF BLOWER WHIRRING)
不要啊 罗素 不!
No, Russell! No!
(GRUNTING)
(WHOOPING)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
啊?
Huh?
罗素?
Russell?
道格!
Dug!
我藏在你的门廊下
我喜欢你 我能留下吗?
DUG: I was hiding under your porch
because I love you. Can I stay?
你能不能留下?
当然了 你是我的狗嘛 对不?
Can you stay?
Well, you're my dog, aren't you?
我是你的主人
And I'm your master.
你是我的主人?
DUG: You're my master?
天啊! 天啊!
Oh, boy! Oh, boy!
好孩子 道格! 你是个好孩子!
CARL: Good boy, Dug!
You're a good boy!
(EXCLAIMING)
好咧!
Yes!
别担心 凯文 我会来救...
Don't worry, Kevin. I'll save...
(GROWLING)
他们一看到你就会相信我的
And they wouldn't believe me.
Just wait till they get a look at you.
主人?
ALPHA: Master?
- 那个小邮差又回来了
- 什么?
- The small mailman has returned.
- What?
放开我
Let me go.
你的老朋友在哪?
Where's your elderly friend?
他已经不是我朋友了
He's not my friend anymore.
你在这里 就说明他也在附近
Well, if you're here,
Fredricksen can't be far behind.
你们把凯文藏哪儿了?
RUSSELL: Where are you
keeping Kevin?
放开我!
Let me go!
想叫就叫吧 小邮差
BETA: Scream all you want,
small mailman.
你的邮差朋友是听不见的
GAMMA: None of your mailman friends
can hear you.
我要展现野外探险训练的成果!
I'll unleash
all my Wilderness Explorer training!
老大 弗雷德里克森s回来了
MUNTZ: Alpha,
Fredricksen's coming back.
看好那只鸟 如果见到那老头
你知道该怎么做
Guard that bird. If you see the old man,
you know what to do.
喂 你们上哪儿去啊?
我还没说完呢！
Hey, where are you going?
I'm not finished with you!
很高兴和你谈话
MUNTZ: Nice talking with you.
啊!
Ahhh!
你在哪儿呢 弗雷德里克森?
Where are you, Fredricksen?
(RUSSELL SCREAMING)
罗素!
Russell!
- 弗雷德里克森先生!
- 道格 把房子转过来!
- Mr. Fredricksen!
- Dug, bring her over!
你回来救凯文啦!
我们去找她吧!
You came back for Kevin!
Let's go get her!
我去找凯文 你留在这里
CARL: I'm getting Kevin. You stay here.
可我想帮你
But I wanna help.
我不需要你帮
I don't want your help.
你安全就好
I want you safe.
(GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
我们怎么绕过这些狗?
How do we get past these dogs?
这儿!
DUG: Point!
凯文
Kevin.
(SQUAWKS)
别担心 凯文 我们马上就到
Don't worry, Kevin. We're on our way.
别让任何人穿过这些门
ALPHA: Allow no one to be entering
through these doors.
看好那只鸟 这是我的命令
Guard well that bird, my minions.
现在我们该怎么办 道格?
What do we do now, Dug?
(GNAWING)
谁想要球?
Who wants the ball?
(DOGS CLAMOURING)
- 我 我要!
- 我要!
DOG 1: Me! I want it!
DOG 2: Me! I do!
- 我要那个球!
- 给我!
DOG 3: I want the ball!
DOG 4: Give it to me!
那就拿去吧!
Then go get it!
我要先到那儿!
GAMMA: I'm gonna get there first!
拿到球了!
GAMMA: Getting the ball!
我拿到了!
GAMMA: I got it!
Uh-oh.
(DOGS GROANING)
对不起 凯文 现在就把你救出去
I'm sorry, Kevin.
Let's get you out of here.
主人 他跑了! 那个老头!
GAMMA: Master! He's gone!
The old man!
他在这里!
DOG 1: He's here!
- 他带走了那只鸟!
- 那只鸟不见了
GAMMA: He's got the bird!
DOG 2: The bird's gone...
安静 一个一个说!
Calm down! One at a time!
我 要 帮 忙!
I... want... to... help!
哈哈!
Ha-ha!
(SCREAMING)
(PANTING)
- 他在D厅!
- 他在C厅!
DOG 3: He's in Hall D!
DOG 4: He's in Hall C!
是那个老头!
DOG 5: It's the old man!
有谁知道他们在哪儿?
Does anyone know where they are?
(GLASS SQUEAKING)
(SCREAMING)
灰狗队长? 把房子撞下来
Gray Leader? Take down the house.
(SCREAMS)
灰狗队长 到位
BETA: Gray Leader, checking in.
灰狗二号 到位
GAMMA: Gray Two, checking in.
灰狗三号 到位
GRAY THREE: Gray Three, checking in.
锁定目标
BETA: Target sighted.
(SCREAMING)
快点 凯文
Come on, Kevin.
(BARKS)
啊!
Auuggghh!
(BARKING)
(GROWLING)
你们好
DUG: Hi.
(MUNTZ GRUNTING)
(YELLS)
(JOINTS CRACKING)
有什么遗言吗 弗雷德里克森?
说吧！都吐出来吧！
Any last words, Fredricksen? Come on!
Spit it out!
- 快走
- 够了
- Come on.
- Enough!
我要把那只鸟带回去 不管死活
I am taking that bird back with me.
Alive or dead!
快走 凯文
Come on, Kevin.
(CARL YELLS)
(DUG WHIMPERS)
(GROWLING)
这下可是正合我意啊 道格
ALPHA: I will have many enjoyments
from what I am about to do, Dug.
(SNARLING)
它戴着耻辱罩!
DOG 1: He wears the Cone of Shame!
什么? 别在那傻站着 进攻!
ALPHA: (IN SQUEAKY VOICE) What?
Do not just continue sitting. Attack!
(ALL LAUGHING)
不不! 别笑了!
把这玩意拿下来!
ALPHA: No, no! Stop your laughing!
Get this off of me!
听着 你们这些狗 坐下!
DUG: Listen, you dog. Sit!
是 老大
ALL: Yes, Alpha.
老大? 我不是老大 它才是
DUG: Alpha? I am not Alpha. He is...
哦!
Oh!
(GRUNTS)
我做不到
I can't do it.
- 罗素!
- 啊?
- CARL: Russell!
- Huh?
嘎 嘎 啊!
CARL: Caw, caw! Raar!
Caw, caw! Raar!
你让弗雷德里克森先生落单了!
You leave Mr. Fredricksen alone!
嘿 是松鼠!
Hey, squirrel!
松鼠? 在哪儿? 哪里? 哪里?
GAMMA: Squirrel? Where?
Where? Where?
松鼠在哪儿?
BETA: Where's the squirrel?
我讨厌松鼠
GAMMA: I hate squirrels.
(SCREAMS)
(GASPS)
道格!
Dug!
主人!
DUG: Master!
罗素! 在这儿 快走!
Russell! Over here! Let's go!
弗雷德里克森先生!
Mr. Fredricksen!
快跑 凯文!
CARL: Go on, Kevin!
(GUN FIRES)
不!
No!
罗素! 快出来!
Russell! Get out of there!
不! 离他们远点!
No! Leave them alone!
罗素 抓住凯文! 别松手!
Russell, hang on to Kevin!
Don't let go of her!
凯文! 巧克力!
Kevin! Chocolate!
(SQUAWKS)
(GASPS)
(PANTING)
酷毙了!
RUSSELL: That was cool!
(ALL LAUGHING)
别转来转去的 孩子!
慢点 罗素
Don't jerk around so much, kid!
Easy, Russell.
好高 都快吓死我了
DUG: Oh, I am ready to not be up high.
真为你的房子难过 弗雷德里克森先生
Sorry about your house,
Mr. Fredricksen.
只是座房子而已
You know, it's just a house.
(CARL LAUGHING)
(CHICKS CHIRPING)
瞧瞧 你多可爱啊
Look at you. You're so soft.
(HONKS)
嗷!
ALL: Aw!
我要是能养一个就好了
I wish I could keep one.
(HISSES)
我的手杖呢? 刚刚还在这儿呢
Where's my cane? I just had it here.
(GAGGING)
算了 你们留着吧
当做我给你们的礼物好了
You know what? Keep them.
A little gift from me to you.
再见 凯文!
Bye, Kevin!
(HONKS)
准备好没?
Ready?
好了
Ready.
(BARKING)
根据收集到的徽章
STRAUCH: And by receiving
their badges,
以下探险者将升级为高级探险者
the following Explorers will graduate
to Senior Explorers.
为表彰其卓越的山地知识
祝贺你 吉米
For Extreme Mountaineering Lore.
Congratulations, Jimmy.
为表彰其野生动物防备技巧
祝贺你 布兰登
For Wild Animal Defensive Arts.
Congratulations, Brandon.
表彰其帮助老人
For Assisting the Elderly...
罗素 有没有人...
Uh, Russell, is there someone that...
不好意思 老头来晚了
Excuse me. Pardon me.
Old man coming through.
我是跟他一起的
I'm here for him.
祝贺你 罗素 先生
Congratulations, Russell. Sir.
罗素 为表彰其帮助老人
Russell, for Assisting the Elderly
以及远超职责的表现
and for performing above
and beyond the call of duty,
我要把我的最高奖章赠与你
I would like to award you
the highest honor I can bestow.
艾丽徽章
The Ellie badge.
哇
Wow.
好了 我想所有人都表彰完毕了
STRAUCH: All right,
I think that covers everybody.
让我们为新当选的
So let's give a big Explorer call
高级野外探险家欢呼吧
to our brand new
Senior Wilderness Explorers.
大家都准备好了吗?
Ready, everybody?
嘎 嘎 啊!
ALL: Caw, caw! Raar!
Caw, caw! Raar!
(DOGS BARKING)
(DOGS HOWLING)
- 蓝色的
- 红色的
- Blue one.
- Red one.
- 蓝色的
- 灰色的
- Blue one.
- DUG: Gray one.
- 红色的
- 那是自行车
- Red one.
- RUSSELL: That's a bike.
是红色的不就行了?
CARL: It's red, isn't it?
弗雷德里克森先生 你在作弊
RUSSELL: Mr. Fredricksen,
you're cheating.
我可没有 又来个红色的
CARL: No, I'm not. Red one.
那是消防龙头
RUSSELL: That's a fire hydrant.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
也许我要配副新眼镜了
CARL: Maybe I need new glasses.
又来辆蓝色的
RUSSELL: Another blue one.
飞屋环游记
-=结束=-
谢谢观看
在前行的路上
Adventure is out there
It's heading our way
让我们展翅高飞
So grab your scarf and goggles
Let's fly
I've mapped out our journey
We're up here to stay
A sunset is our home
A moonbeam we will own
My spirit of adventure is you
Freaks of nature span a globe
That's too big to deny
With canine guards we'll travel there
and spit into their eye
Bang, bang
Once the smoke has cleared
After all the crowds have cheered
We'll make it a joint venture
Before we're in our dentures
My spirit of adventure is you
Adventure is out there
Let's crack some champagne
I've hung a hundred heads
on my wall
To say that I'm traveled
is far too mundane
Let's grab our aero-fare
The high-brows will be there
The spirit of adventure
is something to indenture
My spirit of adventure is you